RESEARCH SUMMARY

Research experience with (1) configuration tuning for distributed systems like Mapreduce, HDFS, Hbase, and Cassandra, (2) concurrency bugs fixing using Hardware Transactions Memory for MySQL, Apache, etc and (3) wireless network security for acoustic eavesdropping.

EDUCATION

The University of Chicago

Ph.D. & M.S. in Computer Science

University of Wisconsin-Madison

M.S. in Computer Engineering (With Thesis)

Harbin Institute of Technology (Main Campus), China

B.E. in Electrical Engineering

Aug 2009 - Jul 2013

Advisor: Xinyu Zhang

Sep 2015 -Dec 2021

Advisor: Shan Lu

Sep 2013 - May 2015

PUBLICATIONS

A Self-Adaptive System for Software Configurations Tuning

Shu Wang, Henry Hoffmann, Shan Lu

(In preparation for submission)

Statically Inferring Performance Properties of Software Configurations

Chi Li, Shu Wang, Henry Hoffmann, Shan Lu

European Conference on Computer Systems(EuroSys), 2020

Acceptance ratio: 18%, 43 out of 234 submissions

Applying Transactional Memory for Concurrency-Bug Failure Recovery in Production Runs

Yuxi Chen, Shu Wang, Shan Lu, Karthikeyan Sankaralingam

IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems (TPDS), 2018

Impact Factor: 3.402

Applying Hardware Transactional Memory for Concurrency-Bug Failure Recovery in Production Runs

Yuxi Chen, Shu Wang, Shan Lu, Karthikeyan Sankaralingam

USENIX Annual Technical Conference (ATC), 2018

Acceptance ratio: 20%, 76 out of 378 submissions

Understanding and Auto-Adjusting Performance-Related Configurations

Shu Wang, Chi Li, William Sentosa, Henry Hoffmann, Shan Lu

ACM International Conference on Architectural Support for Programming Languages and Operating Systems (ASPLOS), 2018

Acceptance ratio: 18%, 56 out of 307 submissions

Fundamental Analysis of Full-duplex Gains in Wireless Networks

Shu Wang, Vignesh Venkateswaran, Xinyu Zhang

IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking (ToN), 2017

Impact Factor: 3.597

Acoustic Eavesdropping through Wireless Vibrometry

Teng Wei, Shu Wang, Anfu Zhou, Xinyu Zhang

ACM International Conference on Mobile Computing and Networking (MobiCom), 2015

Acceptance ratio: 18%, 38 out of 207 submissions, one of top 9 pre-accepted papers

Exploring Full-Duplex Gains in Multi-Cell Wireless Networks: A Spatial Stochastic Framework Shu Wang, Vignesh Venkateswaran, Xinyu Zhang

IEEE Conference on Computer Communications (INFOCOM), 2015

Acceptance ratio: 19\%, 316 out of 1640 submissions

PATENTS

Wireless Vibometer with Antenna Array

Xinyu Zhang, Teng Wei, Shu Wang, Anfu Zhou

POSTERS

Repeatability as Side-Effect in Testbed

Shu Wang, Zhuo Zhen, Jason Anderson, Kate Keahey

ACM/IEEE Supercomputing Conference (Supercomputing), 2018

RESEARCH EXPERIENCES

Automatic Configuration for Software

Apr 2016 - Present

Research Assistant

Uchicago

- Investigated the correlation between configuration and performance.
- Proposed a new configuration framework.
- Proposed control-theatrical based solutions for auto-adjusting configurations.

Hardware Transactional Memory Application

Jan 2016 - Aug 2016

Research Assistant

Uchicago

Explored Intel Hardware Transactional Memory to improve software reliability.

Fine-grained Wireless Sensing Application

Aug 2014 - Mar 2015

Research Assistant

UW madison

• Implemented an eavesdropping system based on the vibration of wireless signal strength.

Stochastic Analysis of Full-duplex Wireless Network

Jan 2014 - Jul 2014

Research Assistant

UWmadison

• Analyzed full-duplex networks capacity using stochastic geometry under different MAC protocols.

INTERN

Argonne National Laboratory (ANL)

Jun 2018 - Sep 2018

TEACHING ASSISTANT

MPCS-51040 C Programming	
CMSC-15400 Introduction to Computer Systems	

Autumn 2015 *Spring 2019*

AWARDS

Student Travel Grant, ASPLOS, Midwest PL Summit	2018
People's Scholarship for Academic Excellence, Three Times	Aug 2009 - Jul 2013
Outstanding Students, Harbin Institute of Technology	2012
Mathematical Contest in Modeling, Honorable Mention	2012
The 3rd China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest, 2nd Prize	2011
Endress + Hauser Enterprise Scholarship	2011
The 2nd China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest, 2nd Prize	2010

SKILLS

- Programming: C, Java, Python, Matlab, PHP, IDE: Emacs, Eclipse, Quartus, IAR, keil, Latex. Verilog.
- Software: Hadoop, HBase, OpenStack.
- Hardware: Intel HTM, Embedded System.
- Platform: WARP, Intel MCS-51, TI CC2530.
- Related Courses: OS, Advanced OS, Algorithms, Database, Wireless and Mobile Networks, Computer Architecture, Advanced Computer Networks, Machine Learning, Deep Learning